so hello everyone it's been a while
since I've done one of these book
reviews but I'm Joe Brewer and I'm a
change strategist and I want to share
with you an amazing book that I recently
read and I have that pleasure of knowing
you author too which is really great is
this one right here money blood and
revolution how Darwin and the doctor of
King Charles the first could turn
economics into a science and it's by
George Cooper so George Cooper is a
financial analyst he lives in the United
Kingdom and among other things he
forecasts he predicted the financial
crisis of 2008 being within I believe he
was a Goldman Sachs at the time and what
he does in this book it's really
phenomenal two things first thing he
does is he tells a story that's very
accessible because he wrote this for his
teenage daughter to answer a question
she had about why economists just don't
seem to understand what's about to
happen with the economy you know if
economists were really good scientists
they'd be able to predict or forecast or
at least explain generally how the
economy behaves and what it's about to
do and of course we know from the 2008
financial collapse that almost none of
them forecast that so clearly there's
something wrong with the throw the
economics so the second thing that he
doesn't this book that's so awesome is
he explains why economics is not yet a
proper science and how it is in the
process of becoming one so just really
be brief background there's this amazing
field of knowledge known as the
philosophy of science that looks at how
scientific revolutions happen so like
how the Copernican revolution led to the
birth of modern astronomy without
understanding of the relationship
between the Earth and the Sun and of all
the planets traveling on the Sun this
was a revolution or a paradigm shift in
science for astronomy that this
understanding of how science is come
into being can be applied to the field
of economics now we apply to economics
what we find is that economics is
currently fragmented and at odds with
itself that there are lots of different
schools of thought there's keen v anism
and there's the
it's called the Austrian school there's
neoliberalism and neoclassical economics
there's ecological economics and
behavioral economics and complexity
economics and thermo economics all these
different fields and there's a
monetarism or looking at it through
monetary theory what's interesting is
that every one of these different fields
is partially correct in some parts of
what it's saying and partially incorrect
and so what that means is that none of
them is able to stand is a proper fully
fledged science on its own but when you
look at all the different pieces you
start to see that there is a coherent
paradigm there's a coherent central
understanding that connects the pieces
that are correct across all of them and
that discards all the pieces that are
not correct so at George Cooper does in
this book money blood and revolution is
he takes the scientific revolutions
around blood around circulation in the
human body and now there's a doctor of
King Charles brought into being a
paradigm for medical science the gave
birth to medicine as a proper science
and he takes the work of Charles Darwin
and biology and shows that all of the
different fragmented ideas about
biological thinking were brought
together and made coherent by a Darwin's
theory of natural selection and that if
we take the same kind of thinking and
actually key findings from Darwinism and
from circulation and medicine that were
able to see what a coherent science of
economics is and so what George Cooper
offers us is a coherent story about how
economics has not yet become a proper
science and how it is becoming one and
in the last few chapters he even offers
his own paradigm kind of conceptual
understanding of what this new paradigm
is about to become and so this is a
great book for anyone who wants to
understand economics as a proper science
or why economics has not yet become one
and now they can help make economics
into a proper science more quickly so I
found it incredibly enlightening very
readable and very enjoyable to read and
I was able to read it in just a couple
of days because it's you can see it's
fairly short
it's written in language that a teenager
can understand and it's incredibly
enlightening for why economics has
failed us up to now and how we can
change that situation so go rap go grab
your own copy today read it and learn a
lot about economics and the history of
science all right enjoy